# Zekarias T. Kefato

# Postdoc researcher

Vita Liljans Väg 66, 127 34, Skärholmen, Sweden

Mobile: (+46) 73 740 6907 Email: zekarias@kth.se Skype: zekarias.tilahun

Homepage: https://zekarias-tilahun.github.io/zack/

### **SUMMARY**

I am a postdoc researcher and the main area of my research is graph based machine learning. Starting from my PhD, I have been doing research on graph representation learning (GRL). My current focus is on Graph Neural Networks, contextualized GRL, and Self-supervised GRL. During my research, I have developed a strong knowledge and a set of skills mainly in the following areas, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Graph Analytics, and Data Visualization.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm/Sweden - Postdoc Researcher

June 2019 - PRESENT

University of Trento, Trento/Italy - Research Assistant

Nov 2013 - Oct 2014

Ethiopian Information Network Security Agency, Addis Ababa/Ethiopia - Software Engineer

Sep 2009 - Aug 2011

I was a full-stack developer using Java & Hibernate, my responsibility was the loan management sub-system of a micro-finance. I have completed designing, developing and deploying the subsystem along with the full system developed by my team. In addition, I was part of a team doing research on Design Patterns.

Microlink Information Technology College, Addis Ababa/Ethiopia - Assistant Lecturer

Feb 2008 - Aug 2009

I taught and assisted undergrad level courses, such as Data structure and analysis, Programming in C++, Object oriented programming in Java, and Artificial Intelligence.

CPU Business and Information Technology College, Addis Ababa/Ethiopia - Guest Lecturer

June 2008 - Sep 2008

TA for undergrad level Artificial Intelligence course.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Trento, Trento/Italy - PhD in Computer Science

Nov 2014 - Apr 2019

University of Trento, Trento/Italy - MSc in Computer Science

Sep 2011 - Oct 2013

Microlink Information Technology College - BSc in Software Engineering

### **Programming and Scripting Languages**

Python, R, JavaScript, Java, C++, Scala, Shell Scripting, SQL

### **Data Science and Machine Learning Tools**

- Machine Learning and Data Management Tools
  - o PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Apache Spark, MySQL
- Data Analysis Libraries
  - O Python: Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, scikit-learn, Networkx, ...
  - R: data.frame, data.table, dplyr, tidyr, tidyverse, ...
- Data Visualization Libraries
  - o *Python*: Plotly, Matplotlib
  - o R: Shiny + Plotly, ggplot
  - o Javascript: Chart.js, Plotly.js

#### **Professional Services**

- I. Reviewer: Elsevier Neurocomputing Journal
- II. *PC Member*: The Seventh IEEE International Conference on Social Networks Analysis, Management and Security
- III. PC Member: The Sixth International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization, and Data Science
- IV. Reviewer: CCGrid2020 (The 20th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Cluster, Cloud and Internet Computing)
- V. Reviewer: Elsevier Pattern Recognition Journal
- VI. Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering Journal
- VII. *PC Member*: The Sixth IEEE International Conference on Social Networks Analysis, Management and Security
- VIII. PC Member: The Fifth International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization, and Data Science
- IX. PC Member: The Fourth International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization, and Data Science

### **Selected Publications**

- 1. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Sarunas Girdzijauskas, Nasrullah Sheikh, and Alberto Montresor. Next Item Prediction using Contextualized Dynamic Embeddings. In Proceedings of the Web Conference 2021 (WWW'21).
- Zekarias T. Kefato, Sarunas Girdzijauskas. SelfGNN: Self-supervised Graph Neural Networks without
  explicit negative sampling. The International Workshop on Self-Supervised Learning for the Web 2021,
  SSL'21 at WWW'21.
- 3. Zamboni, Simone, **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Sarunas Girdzijauskas, Noren Christoffer and L. D. Col. "Pedestrian Trajectory Prediction with Convolutional Neural Networks." ArXiv abs/2010.05796 (2020) (Under review: Elsevier Pattern Recognition Journal).
- 4. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Sarunas Girdzijauskas. Gossip and Attend: Context-sensitive Graph Representation Learning. In Proceedings of the Fourteenth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media (ICWSM 2020)
- 5. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Sarunas Girdzijauskas. Graph Neighborhood Attentive Pooling. ArXiv abs/2001.10394 (2020).
- 6. **Zekarias T. Kefato** and Nasrullah Sheikh and Alberto Montresor. Which way? Direction-Aware Attributed Graph Embedding. GEM'2020. Sep 2020.

- 7. Nasrullah Sheikh, **Zekarias T. Kefato**, and Alberto Montresor. A simple approach to attributed graph embedding via enhanced autoencoder. In Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Complex Networks and Their Applications (COMPLEX NETWORKS 2019), December 2019.
- 8. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Nasrullah Sheikh, Leila Bahri, Amira Soliman, Alberto Montresor and Sarunas Girdzijauskas. CAS2VEC: Network-Agnostic Cascade Prediction in Online Social Networks. IEEE SNAMS'18, Valencia, Spain October 2018, 8 pages (Best Paper).
- 9. Nasrullah Sheikh and **Zekarias T. Kefato** and Alberto Montresor. Semi-Supervised Heterogeneous Information Network Embedding for Node Classification Using 1D-CNN. SNAMS'18, Oct 2018.
- Zekarias T. Kefato, Nasrullah Sheikh, and Alberto Montresor. REFINE: Representation Learning from Diffusion Events. Fourth International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization and Big Data, Voltera, Tuscany, Italy, September 2018, 12 pages.
- 11. Nasrullah Sheikh, **Zekarias T. Kefato**, and Alberto Montresor. GAT2VEC: Representation learning for attributed graphs. Computing Journal, 2018.
- 12. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Nasrullah Sheikh, and Alberto Montresor. Mineral: Multi-modal Network Representation Learning. Third International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization and Big Data, Voltera, Tuscany, Italy, September 2017, 12 pages
- 13. **Zekarias T. Kefato**, Nasrullah Sheikh, and Alberto Montresor. DeepInfer: Diffusion Network Inference through Representation Learning. In Proceedings of 13th International Workshop on Mining and Learning with Graphs, MLG'17, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, August 2017, 8 pages

## **Programming Languages**

- 1. Received the Best Paper Award for IEEE SNAMS 2018.
- 2. Gold Medalist for the highest GPA from Microlink Information Technology College 2007 graduates
- 3. Certificate of Merit for the best final project of Software Engineering graduates of Microlink Information Technology College, 2007

# Languages

	Language	Level
1.	Amharic	Native
2.	English	Proficient
3.	Italian	Conversational

### References

Name	Email	Affiliation
Sarunas Girdzijauskas	sarunasg@kth.se	Postdoc Supervisor
Alberto Montresor	alberto.montresor@unitn.it	PhD Advisor
Themis Palpanas	themis@mi.parisdescartes.fr	MSc Thesis Advisor